ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers, 5780/052
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers
1952-1980
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Assistant President
5780/052
32.5 cubic feet
32.5 linear feet
Records
Chiefly correspondence and articles with and by Gus Tyler from the 1950s to the 1970s.
3671900
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Robert Lazar
Date completed:
1981
EAD encoding:
Casey Westerman, 2002Cheryl Beredo, June 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
Gus Tyler, author, commentator, educator, political leader, and official, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU).
Gus Tyler was born in New York in 1911. He attended New York University on a scholarship in the early 1930s, where he became involved in left-wing political activities. After graduating in 1933, Tyler briefly worked as a writer for the Jewish Daily Forward. His sharp intellect and socialist politics caught the attention of ILGWU president David Dubinsky, who hired Tyler to work in the union's Education Department. Tyler left the ILG after a few years to work with the Socialist Party, but returned in the late 1930s. He held a number of positions in the union and in 1945 became Assistant President, which position he held until 1989. Tyler is the author of many articles and books on labor, labor history, economics, and other topics, and for many years has hosted his own radio program on station WEVD in New York. He has also served as an adjunct faculty member at a number of universities and colleges in the U.S., and worked with the ILGWU's successor union, UNITE, as an assistant to the president. Tyler died on June 3, 2011 in Sarasota, Florida.
Scope and Contents
Chiefly correspondence and articles with and by Gus Tyler from the 1950s to the 1970s.
Organizations include: the AFL-CIO; the American Association of Political Consultants; Americans for Democratic Action; the American Veterans Committee; the Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies; the Democratic Party; the Fashion Institute of Technology; Histadrut; the Hudson Institute; the Jewish Labor Committee; The League for Industrial Democracy; the Liberal Party (New York State); locals and departments of the ILGWU; the NAACP; the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations (Cornell University); and the Socialist Party. Subjects include economic policy and conditions in the U.S.; electoral reform; politics in the U.S., especially in New York City and State; social conditions in the U.S.; the Vietnam War; voter registration; and worker training and education.
Series I consists of Tyler's correspondence. Series II is made up of subject files, dealing with both union and non-union matters. Series III contains both correspondence with and articles by Tyler. Individuals represented include: Abraham Beame; Sol Chaikin; Wilbur Daniels; David Dubinsky; Arthur J. Goldberg; Andrew M. Greeley; Averell Harriman; Hubert Humphrey; Jay Lovestone; George McGovern; John F. Kennedy; Robert F. Kennedy; Charles Silberman; Leon Stein; Philip Taft; and Abraham Weiss.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/088. ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers
5780/096. ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers
General
"Permanent Deposit"
Arrangement
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Elections--United States.; Labor unions -- Officials and employees; Labor union locals; Working class -- Education -- United States; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.; Voter registration--United States.; United States -- Social conditions -- 1945-; United States -- Economic conditions -- 1945-; United States -- Economic policy -- 1961-1971; United States -- Economic policy -- 1971-1981; United States -- Politics and government -- 1945-1989; New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 1951-; New York (N.Y.) -- Politics and government -- 1951-; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Beame, Abraham D.(Abraham David), 1906-; Chaikin, Sol C.; Daniels, Wilbur, 1923-; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982; Goldberg, Arthur J.; Greeley, Andrew M., 1928-; Harriman, W. Averell(William Averell), 1891-1986.; Humphrey, Hubert H.(Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Kennedy, John F.(John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968.; Lovestone, Jay.; McGovern, George S.(George Stanley), 1922-; Silberman, Charles E., 1925-2011.; Stein, Leon, 1912-; Taft, Philip, 1902-1976.; Tyler, Gus.; Tyler, Gus.; Weiss, Abraham, 1895-1970.; AFL-CIO; American Association of Political Consultants; American Veterans Committee; Americans for Democratic Action; Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies; Democratic Party (U.S.); Fashion Institute of Technology (New York, N.Y.); Histadrut ha-kelalit shel ha-ʻovdim be-Erets-Yiśra'el; Hudson Institute; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. --Management.; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); League for Industrial Democracy; Liberal Party of New York State; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; Socialist Party (U.S.)
3671900
- Series I. General correspondence, 1957-1979
  - General Correspondence, 1957-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series II. Subject files., 1948-1979
  - Academy For Contemporary Problems, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Advertising and Public Relations, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Scope and Contents
    Incl. corres. and reports from Green Dolmatch Inc., re 75 anniversary of Union.
  - Advertising and Public Relations (Newsom, Earl & Company), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Advocates - TV program on "Day Care Centers" w. G.T. participating, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    May 1972.
  - The Advocates - "Imports and the Multi­national Corporation", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    March 1972.
  - The Advocates - "Social Security", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    January 1973.
  - African Trade Union Training Program, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Association of Political Consultants, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    1973-June 1974.
  - American Association of Political Consultants, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    July 1974-1975.
  - American Association of Political Consultants, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Corres. re Politeia, quarterly of the AAPC.
  - American Association of Political Consultants, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    (Issues of) Politeia, G.T. Editor.
  - AFL-CIO, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Incl. G.T. statement at Industrial Union Department Conference on International Trade and Jobs, April 1977; article "We're Pleading on Behalf of All Americans", 1977; G.T. memo to Pres. Sol C. Chaikin on "The New Right", 1978.
  - American Immigration and Citizenship Conference, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Incl. G.T. paper "The White Worker", May 1970; "Economic Factors in Group Life", paper prepared for the Task Force on Group Life in America, June 1971.
  - American Jewish Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Incl. G.T. paper on "Confronting Scarcity", 1974.
  - American Jewish Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    May 1974-1975. Incl. transcript of interview w. G.T. for the William E. Weiner Oral History Library of the AJC, September 1974.
  - American Jewish Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Incl. G.T. speech, May 1976.
  - American Labor's Stake and Voice in a Changing World Economy (Conferences), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Incl. G.T. paper for December 1976 conference "The Threat to American Manufacture".
  - American Symphony Orchestra, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - American Veterans Committees, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Incl. G.T. paper "The Future of American Labor", presented at June 12-25, Executive Program (Aspen, Colorado).
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies [folder 1 of 2], 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies [folder 2 of 2], 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Athletic Federation of Spanish Amateur Leagues of New York, Inc., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Baranson, Jack, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Incl. Baranson article in Foreign Affairs, Winter 1976-77, "Technology Exports Can Hurt Us".
  - Beame, Abe, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Memo on ILGWU activities in campaign to elect Beame (for Mayor of N.Y.C.).
  - Benefits Department ILGWU and Related Union Matters, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Brandeis University, 1969-1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn College of the City of New York, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Business International Corporation, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - C, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Carter, James E., 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Material on preparation for "Garment Center Rally".
  - Center for War/Peace Studies, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions/The Fund for the Republic, Inc., 1963-1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Incl. corres. re conference "The Corporation and the Quality of Life", 1971.
  - Chaikin, Sol C. (and Wilbur Daniels), 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    1973-September 10, 1975. Memos & letters on pending matters.
  - Chaikin, Sol C. (and Wilbur Daniels), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    September 1 1975- October 1975.
  - Chaikin, Sol C. {and Wilbur Daniels), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    November 1975.
  - Chaikin, Sol C. (and Wilbur Daniels), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    December 1975.
  - Chaikin, Sol C. (and Wilbur Daniels), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    January-March 16, 1976,
  - Chaikin, Sol C. (and Wilbur Daniels), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    March 17, 1976-July 1976.
  - Chaikin, Sol C., 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    August-December 1976.
  - Chaikin, Sol C., 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    January-May 1977.
  - Chaikin, Sol C., 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    July-August 1977.
  - Chaikin, Sol C., 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    September-December 1977.
  - Character Foundations, Inc. Campaign in conducting strike against firm, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Citizens Committee for New York City, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Civil Service Commission, U.S., 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Corres. re G.T. addressing Executive Seminar Center Programs, Kings Point, N.Y.
  - Cloak Joint Board (N.Y.), 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cloak Out-Of-Town Department, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Incl. corres. re Rutgers' Seminar, 1972.
  - Columbia School of Social Work, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Corres. re Union Health Center social service center in cooperation w. Columbia.
  - Columbia University School of Social Work, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Commission of Human Resources, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    (created by the National Academy of Sciences)
  - Committee for National Constitutional Convention, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Political Education, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Congress, 1975-1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut University, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Corres. re establishing a labor center.
  - Conventions, ILGWU (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cornell University-New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1967-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Incl. G.T. course 1972-73, "Contemporary Labor Problems".
  - Cornell University, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Council for the Progress of Nontraditional Study, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    (created by Institute for Educational Development)
  - Daniels, Wilbur, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Letters & memos.
  - Daniels, Wilbur, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Letters & memos, G.T. memo to S.C. Chaikin re campaign against imports, 1975; Gallup Study of Communications Credibility conducted for the ILGWU, 1976.
  - D'Armigene Firm, New York, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - D'eloia, Angelo, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Corres. re. case of D'eloia blacklisted because of his support of Administration's (Kennedy) Medical-Care Program,
  - Day Care Centers, 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Party, 1970-1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Democratic Party, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Democratic Committee on National Priorities
  - Democratic Party, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Democratic National Convention, N.Y.C. Incl. G.T. testimony at Democratic National Platform Committee.
  - Democratic Party, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Democratic Party Conference (mini convention) Kansas City
  - Democratic Party, 1970-1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    New York City & State Committee
  - Democratic Party, 1969-1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Party Structure
  - Directors Meetings, Education Department, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Dubinsky, David, 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Dubinsky, David, Foundation, 1967-1976 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    February 3, 1967, February 19, 1976.
  - Dubrow, Evelyn, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Duke University - Law and Contemporary Problems, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Corres. re G.T. articles. Incl. "Court vs. Legislature (The Socio-Politics of Malapportionment) Spring 1962.
  - E, 1958-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Education, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Incl. G.T. article "The Role of Organized Labor- A Fool's View of Career Education" at conference on Career Education, Educational Testing Service, May.
  - Education, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Incl. G.T. paper "What Kind of Career Education", presented at Career Education Fellowship seminar, April; "A Labor View of the 'New Class'", October.
  - Education, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Incl. Mark Schulman paper "Issues and Strategies for Enhancing the Participation of Labor in the Implementation of Career Education", November 1976.
  - Education, 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Fund for Adult Education.
  - Education, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Governor's Task Force for State Aid to Education (N.Y.)
  - Educational Television, 1961-1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Electoral Reform. [folder 1 of 2], 1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Incl. G.T. statement on proposed changes in the Presidential election process, March.
  - Electoral Reform. [folder 1 of 2], 1969 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Electoral Reform, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Employment, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Incl. conference on full employment (national), 1974.
  - Encampment for Citizenship, 1957-1968 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Equal Opportunity Union Made, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Corres. re publication.
  - Evening Institute, ILGWU, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Statistical information.
  - Fashion Capital of the World, Inc., N.Y.C., 1975 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology, 1957-1972 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology, 1973-1978 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Federation of Union Representatives, 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Affairs Task Force, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    (established by the Democratic Advisory Council of Elected Officials)
  - Form Letters, 1973-1978 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Freedom of Residence Foundation, Inc., 1961-1963 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Frontlash, 1968-1977 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    (student youth project for grassroots voter registration and political education).
  - G, 1957-1963 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Garment Industry Productivity Seminar (sponsored by Association and the Union), 1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - General Electric Strike, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Girl Scouts of the U.S.A., 1976 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Corres. re Co-Ed Garment Co., maker of Girl Scout uniforms leaving Festus, Missouri.
  - Golberg, Arthur J., 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Greeley, Andrew M., 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - H, 1961-1963 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hampshire College (Amherst, Mass.), 1969-1975 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Harriman, Averell, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Independent Labor Committee for the Harriman Ticket. Corres., & receipts; Wilbur Daniels, Treasurer.
  - Health Security, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Corres. re National Health Security Bill.
  - Hernandez, Aileen C. (Director of Public Relations and Education) Pacific Coast Region, ILGWU) re union activities. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - High School of Fashion Industries, 1958-1966 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - High School of Fashion Industries, 1968-1976 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Histadrut, 1963-1975 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Incl. G.T. paper "The International Role of American Labor", May conference.
  - Hudson Institute, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hudson Institute, 1973-1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hughes, Stuart, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    (Candidate for U.S. Senate, Mass.).
  - Humphrey, Hubert h., 1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    May, 1967. Breakfast meeting arranged by Union.
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1967-1975 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Incl. letters.
  - Hunter College, 1971-1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Incl. course material taught by G.T., 1971.
  - Import-Export (Multinationals), 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Import-Export (Multinationals), 1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    January-September 1973. Incl. corres. re Burke-Hartke Bill, H.R. 62.
  - Import-Export (Multinationals), 1973 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    October-December 1973. Incl. G.T. article, "Labor's Multinational Pains". A reprint from Foreign Affairs; draft paper, "Trade and Multinationals" submitted to Democratic Task Force", C.
  - Import-Export (Multinationals), 1975 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    July 1975. Incl. Sol C. Chaikin statement & analysis submitted for the Research Department before the Trade Policy Staff Committee on Women's & Children's Apparel Industry and Multi­lateral Trade Negotiations, July 1975.
  - Import-Export (Multinationals), 1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    August-December 1975.
  - Import-Export (Multinationals), 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Incl. G.T. testimony on trade before Subcommittee on International Economic Policy, February 1976; article "Technology Transfer: A Labor View", March 1977 and; "America's Great Export Jobs", 1977.
  - Import-Export (Multinationals), 1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Industrial Relations Counselors, Inc., 1969-1977 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Institute for the Future, 1975-1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Incl. G.T. paper "Technology Transfer: A Labor View", March 1977.
  - Institute of International Education, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Institute for Politics and Planning, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Institute for World Order, Inc. (formerly Institute for International Order), 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - International Association of Governmental Labor Officials, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Inter-departmental Memoranda, 1974-1976 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - ILGWU Campaign Committee, 1970-1973 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Memoranda, corres. re election campaign rules & regulations & related matters.
  - ILGWU Campaign Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - ILGWU Cooperative Houses, 1968-1976 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - ILGWU - Educational Department, 1937-1964 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Incl. educational material from affiliated locals.
  - ILGWU Education Department, 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - ILGWU Political Department, 1948-1950 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Corres. & political bulletins.
  - ILGWU Political Department, 1955-1963 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - ILGWU Political Department, 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1958-1962 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Corres.
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1963-1969 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1958-1963 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Educational Testing Service.
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Finalists & winners.
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1962-1965 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1961-1964 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Ltrs. from winners who graduated.
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1956-1961 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Local scholarship fund.
  - ILGWU Scholarship Fund, 1962-1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)